Why are cave raider maps so vague, anyway?
They say it's to prevent unauthorized cave raiding.
Details of locations are only taught, not written down. Though, for me...
You got your info from Ozen and Lyza's envelope.
It'll be all right, Nanachi. Let's trust in Riko and keep going!
Fine by me. We gotta respect our team leader's opinion.
We're here.
The Garden of the Flowers of Fortitude.
These are all Eternal Fortunes!
Don't go up to the top of the hill. You'll get hit with the strains.
Okay!
It's the same place I saw back then.
Reg, what's wrong?
Nothing!
I'm coming now.
Nanachi!
I heard it too.
There's several of 'em.
Riko!
At the foot of the hill... Cave raiders!
Several of them have collapsed!
We have to save— I mean...
Can I go see what's going on?
Don't get caught.
And remember, my orders are...
...absolute!
All right, go ahead.
Riko, if you see anything strange, tell me.
Okay!
I'll watch over the force field.
The consciousnesses are in total disarray...
They confused or something?
Huh?
What's up?
The thing that person's carrying...
Is that...
Reg, stop!
Why... Why are they here?
What's wrong, Nanachi?
He's a member of the Umbra Hands,
the personal cave-raider squad of the Sovereign of Dawn, Bondrewd!
Bondrewd...
The one who made you and Mitty suffer?!
At your feet!
In front, on your right!
Was that screaming a moment ago your doing?!
Say something!
Quiet. You'll wake them.
Indeed, I did cause it.
Incidentally, this area has been designated off-limits for over 60 surface-time days now.
What?
So you entered without knowing, then.
Well, that's understandable.
Is this...
It really is the Blaze Reap!
Don't drop it again.
How did...
I want to reiterate that this area is off-limits.
Tell the furry one and your other friend, too.
How do—
Reg! Don't say any more than you have to!
That bastard! I've been under surveillance?
How long has he been watching?
Nanachi, are you all right?
I'll try to find out what he's up to.
Hey! Wait, that's...
Leave it to me.
Any enemy of yours is an enemy of mine!
Hey! I'll decide what I'm gonna do after I see what it is you're doing!
Follow me.
This is... an insect.
It looks just like a leaf.
Huh?
This is...
Riko?
What are you...
Found it!
Nanachi, look!
"Be careful in the flower fields of the sixth layer.
If you spot one of these guys among the leaves, you've found their nest.
They disguise themselves as Flowers of Fortitude
and attack and implant their larvae inside organisms that come near them."
Who?
They were discovered just recently.
The larvae enter the head
and create the perfect living meal for themselves.
Innumerable primeval creatures have been turned into living food sources, as well.
So that's why it's off-limits...
They've already created a massive nest within that hill,
and the insect's predatory adult form is spread throughout the flower garden,
sleeping and waiting for the signal.
"Signal"?
Who?
Hey, it went in his mouth!
They feed themselves to their victims so as to make the living food sources last longer.
I've already collected a specimen from one of their abdomens.
It was then that he let out a scream—
Excuse me. A reflexive utterance.
That was what you heard.
These creatures, which are called "amaranthine-deceptors,"
came from the sixth layer and,
by all rights, should not be here.
Their numbers have proven to be unmanageable.
So, your boss... What is he doing?
The person you speak of isn't currently present.
The method for spanning layers is prone to difficulties.
Who?
That's the signal.
I must hurry.
What are you talking about?!
Burning agents have been dispersed in key areas around the region.
Wh-What are you doing?!
Aren't there still cave raiders out there?!
The adult insects are entering their active period.
There's no saving them.
That can't be!
Then I'll... I can...
Reg!
You can... do what, exactly?
Don't be stupid!
I can't protect Riko on my own! Get back here!
Nothing. I can't do anything, either.
Return to your friends.
The Sovereign of Dawn is eagerly awaiting the arrival of you all.
As for what a decent person would do,
or my pride as a cave raider,
I have no need for such concerns.
Don't lose sight of what you must protect!
Don't lose sight of it!
Damn it!
They're going for any orifice they can!
Ouch!
Ow!
We even got outta their territory—damn persistent things.
Reg's here!
Are you two okay?
You're drenched in bug juice, you know.
The insects are bad enough, but the inferno is consuming all the air, too.
Let's hurry and get out of here.
Nanachi... sorry.
Things went south before I could figure out how they were watching you.
Don't worry about it.
No way you could've seen this coming.
This is awful.
The field of flowers that Mom loved...
The Sovereign of Dawn is eagerly awaiting the arrival of you all.
That bastard...
Looks like I'm not the only one he's been watching.
What lies at the end of this journey?
They still do not know.
What lies on the path ahead?
Right now, there is but one thing they do know.
That, in the depths of this chasm, someone is waiting.
No matter who that may be, they must push forward.
For unless they pass through the darkest of the dark, the dawn shall not come.
Dawn of the Deep Soul
Fifth Layer
The Sea of Corpses
I came from the lowest part of the depths' fifth layer,
from the place they call "Ido Front."
It's Bondrewd's own little sandbox, and the final point from which a person can return and still remain human.
The only entrance to the sixth layer, which White Whistles use for their last dives, is also held within.
But I don't think Bondrewd will just let you guys pass through.
We can't avoid a showdown with him.
So keep your guard up.
See, you are swelled up where you got bitten!
I told you I'm fine, didn't I?
What's that?
A water support probably collapsed.
Seems a path has formed. Let's proceed with caution.
Hey, it's not gonna crumble from under us, right?
Don't be afraid.
We're not walking on any old frost.
They're crystallized water supports.
A little jumping around won't hurt 'em.
That said... I don't sense any living creatures at all.
Is there not any life around here?
Let me think...
Oh, hamashiramas!
Hamashirama
Is that thing edible?
Yeah, apparently it's not poisonous.
Salt made by drying seaweed
Rub the meat well
Seems like there's twice as much slime as flesh...
If you overdo it, it'll get tough.
Apparently it tastes best raw.
Honestly, this'll take some courage.
Don't make that sound!
It's sweet!
Riko Sashimi
The flavor really hits the spot!
You can't judge based on looks alone, huh?!
Yep!
Look, Riko. What a wonderful sight that is.
Hey, Nanachi.
Wanna make the other one into a stew?
For real?!
Hey, Riko, can you teach me how to make it?
Sure! Let's cook it together!
You were really enthusiastic about being taught, huh?
I'm the industrious type, ya see.
I'm not satisfied with being on the same level as you.
And you know, Mitty...
Tasteless food bars were all she ever ate while in the Abyss.
So, that's why...
I've gotta become able to cook good food.
If I'm able to see Mitty again...
I might get to feed her some.
I feel bad that we weren't able to eat stuff this delicious together.
Nanachi!
You're such a good person!
Don't take advantage of the situation to rub me!
Get off me!
Jeez... I'm just trying to have the right attitude, you know.
I don't actually think I'll get to see her again.
Don't say stuff like that!
He's right!
It's too early to give up!
I mean, this is the Abyss, after all!
I bet we'll find a way to see Mitty again,
figure out the reason the Curse of the Abyss exists,
and come to understand the secrets of the Hollows and the relics!
The answers await at the bottom of the netherworld!
The netherworld's bottom...
Considering we don't even know what it's like, you sure are confident, huh?
Of course I am!
After all, that's where Reg comes from!
I'm sure it's a wonderful place!
Come on, you two! Let's go!
Darn it.
This is the adventure to the bottom of this world that I've always wanted.
This is actually really fun...
Darn it...
Lower Region of the Fifth Layer
Forward Operating Base
Ido Front
Lower Region of the Fifth Layer
Forward Operating Base
Ido Front
That building's slowly spinning around!
How's it do that?
Nanachi, you all right?
Yeah, I was just watching the force field is all.
Look! There's a part that doesn't revolve, see?
Unless you use a boat, that's the only entrance.
There's no way to approach without being in clear view.
We'll just have to stay alert as we go.
By the way, that place makes use of the ruins of what was once a ritual site thousands of years ago.
You see that tower in the middle?
That's the device for taking one's last dive into the sixth layer.
Wow, really?!
A ritual site is a place where people pray, right?
I wonder if the ancients saw everything below this point as special, just like we do.
No way...
They're all about the same size as me!
No, stop. Put on a strong face!
So, what should we do now?
We're not sure how much they know.
Don't speak carelessly.
Provoke them into doing the talking.
Information is power.
No matter what they say, don't get scared. And don't miss anything.
Roger that.
Do you know her?
Nope...
So you're Papa's guests?
Pretty small, aren't you?
"Papa"?
Let's go.
But you did do well to make it here considering you're just kids.
Hey!
So how'd you come down here? Tell me!
We used crystallized water supports to—
You're kidding, right?!
You crossed over the crystallized water supports?!
Information is power!
You must be joking! I mean, you never know when one of those things'll collapse!
I've seen them before, you know.
I can tell that you're lying.
So, how'd you really get here?!
You gonna say something or what?
Are you angry 'cause I said you were lying?
Hey, don't give me the silent treatment.
Oh, hey! Do you wanna touch my hat?
Why's she being so casual?
Can you two help me out here?!
P-Please talk... Don't be mean...
Names! We forgot names!
I'm Prushka! And you all are?
R-Reg.
I'm Riko!
And this one here?
You're all fluffy and cute, aren't you?
Are those ears real?
Can you talk?
Papa!
Hello there, everyone. How nice of you to come.
Nanachi.
I'm glad to see you're well.
That hat suits you very nicely.
Oh, that's right, that child's flesh lamp went out the other day.
Congratulations, Nanachi.
Finally been set free, eh?
Hey.
It was you, wasn't it?
You did that to those two, didn't you?!
Bondrewd.
Right now, I don't feel like getting into it.
We just wanna keep on going. Will ya let us pass through?
Certainly! I don't mind in the least.
However, the altar used for taking one's last dive is activated by a white whistle.
I presume you're aware, but a white whistle can only be used by its original owner.
This was made out of a relic called
"Your Worth," the life-reverberating stone.
Even for a parent and child, the timbre won't be produced if the life-insignias differ.
Riko, is that true?
That's what Habo-san said... and Ozen-san, too.
Unlike other whistles, that one can only be used by its original owner.
That white whistle's the key.
You guys won't be able to do anything with it, though.
I thought if I just went, it'd all work out somehow.
We've been through a lot, but I thought that
the three of us would be able to figure something out.
Hey, Papa. Is that girl the White Whistle's kid?
That's right, Prushka.
Can you try to get along with her?
Yep!
Very good. You are truly a good child, aren't you?
I have prepared a room for you all.
Why don't you have a little rest and think things over?
Prushka, you'll show them the way, won't you?
Yep!
Come on! I cleaned it myself, you know!
Let's go, Riko.
Yeah.
The toilet's in there.
You'll die if you fall in, so be careful, okay?
Those stairs are off-limits. You'll get hit with the strain of ascending.
This is your room.
You turn this spinny thing to the left.
Go on in!
These are type-4 energy rations!
They're just those food bars...
They're made for cave raiders who go deeper than the fourth layer.
They've got all the nutrients you need!
Can I eat some?
Of course!
I don't want any.
This tastes like a wall...
Hey. You're Riko, right?
Mm-hmm!
What does "Riko" mean?
What does my name mean?
I wonder...
Guess I don't know.
You know, my name "Prushka" means "the flower of dawn"!
Papa named me that!
Have you ever seen a dawn?
Prushka, have you never been up to the surface?
No, I haven't.
I was born here.
Oh, but... I do know what a dawn is, though!
It's, uh...
When the light comes on!
So, you haven't seen the sea, then?
So when he conducted those brutal experiments,
No, but... it's water, right?
he already had a daughter?
What's he trying to accomplish by having her get close to us?
There's plenty of that down here!
But, the sea's really big, you know?
But that's all it is, right?
So the one down here's more amazing.
Then, what about the second layer's Inverted Forest?
The trees grow upside down,
and the waterfalls even flow upward!
Really?!
Didn't I tell you guys that information is power?
Even in the fifth layer I've never seen anything like that.
You know, I was at this place called Belchero Orphanage, and...
Oh, well...
Unlike outside, it's safe in here.
Have a good rest!
Thanks.
Good night.
Good night, Prushka.
I'm gonna... get some sleep.
Good night.
There's no telling what's going to happen.
Guess I'll stay prepared to take action as I rest.
Hey, that pattern of yours...
Yeah.
It appears every time I put my helmet on.
Think it's some kind of writing?
Huh? Compared to before, it seems like it's...
...fading, doesn't it?
That looks like the same pattern.
This is a relic that produces air.
But every time you use it, the pattern fades a little.
I've seen this on lots of different relics.
The pattern shows the number of uses left until something's unusable—no exceptions.
B-But, even though it's faded some, I've been fine, haven't I?!
Probably means the amount of energy you use to move is insignificant.
There's only one thing I can think of...
the "Incinerator," your cremation cannon.
After all, in a sense it's powerful enough to rewrite the rules of the netherworld.
Judging from the pattern,
you have about three uses left.
You can't go firing the Incinerator.
But...
I can't protect Riko, remember?
The moment you return to being a hunk of
scrap iron is the moment this adventure ends.
If I can't use the Incinerator, how will I be able to take him on if it comes to that?
We'll think of something.
Some way...
Isn't there some way to let them continue onward?
It'll be all right!
Sure enough, you are...
You are all miracles brought forth by the wonder of the Abyss.
How very happy I am that you have returned to me.
Bondrewd.
I have something to discuss.
As do I.
Let us take our time and talk things over.
Gotta pee...
Huh?
Where is everyone?
Oh, right... That must be it.
I'm sure the two of them went to the bathroom together.
Where does this lead down to?
Reg!
Nanachi!
Where did they go?
And the door we came in from is closed and won't open.
The only place left is...
Those stairs are off-limits. You'll get hit with the strain of ascending.
Bondrewd in particular is an out-and-out scoundrel.
You better be careful.
I have a bad feeling about this...
It's all right.
Take it slow.
If it gets dangerous, squat down right away.
Hasn't hit me yet...
It's scary...
But the thought of finding something out after it's too late and regretting it...
is even scarier.
What?
It doesn't hurt...
Huh?
What's going on?
That's right... I've gotta squat down.
But, hold on...
Which way's the ground?
I can't hear my voice.
I can't touch myself.
What's happening to the shape of my body?
Is my face supposed to be farther back?
"Back"... Where is that again?
Where is... where again?
Riko...
Riko!
What a relief!
Prushka...
Ouch!
Your sense of pain's returning, huh?
Show me your face.
Whoa, you hurt yourself really bad.
All of a sudden, I felt sharp things cutting me everywhere.
You fell face first, you know.
Huh?!
The fifth layer's Curse takes away your sense of touch and balance.
Say "Aah."
Aah.
Your molars got messed up...
Once you're no longer able to feel things,
doing something like gritting your teeth can chip 'em really easily.
The cracked ones are baby teeth.
You're in luck! You'll have new ones come in.
That should do it.
Thanks.
Prushka, where were you anyway?
I was in my room.
Your screaming woke me up, you know.
But all the doors were locked...
Oh come on, even I lock my room, you know.
I mean, I'm at that age, so I've got my reasons.
You know, the truth is...
How'd it go?
You're right, it sure is strange.
They're all locked. Pretty sure that's never happened before.
And so... this is the only way left.
Reg... Nanachi...
All right! Let's go together.
Huh?! But...
It'll be okay.
Meinya, wake up!
Huh?!
This is Meinya. Papa gave her to me on my tenth birthday.
Come on, Meinya, say hi to Riko.
There! You go first!
Will Meinya be okay?
Meinya's eyes and legs sense different things than we do.
You know...
They say that the only senses the fifth layer's Curse can take away are those possessed by humans.
Whoa...
Just leave it to me. There's a trick to this.
I mean, even I have lots of secret adventures Papa doesn't know about.
Hey, Prushka.
In your eyes, what kind of person is your dad?
My Papa's the best!
He's always thinking of me!
I never would have imagined you'd have a daughter.
Our blood relationship is weak, but she is my daughter.
Is she not adorable?
So she's not directly descended from you?
I mean, it's not like you could start a family, could you?
Nanachi, is what they call "family" restricted merely to those related by blood?
I do not believe that to be so.
Families are built by strangers who cross paths and come together.
Having souls that love each other is what makes people family.
Blood merely helps in that regard.
Love. It's a matter of love, Nanachi.
"Love," you say?
You've got some nerve to spew such grand concepts from that narrow little opening!
Even your venomous words are unique and adorable.
That's it, take a deep whiff.
You're new at this, so just keep your eyes closed and concentrate.
Even if you lose all your senses,
you can see the waves Meinya is putting out in front of us, right?
Yep, I can see them!
Take your time and head for those.
Slowly... Go slowly forward.
Just like that, Riko.
Nanachi, at long last the research is entering its final stage.
Please, come back and join me again.
There are so many things I would like you to see.
Hey, Bondrewd...
I... I, uh...
All right, I'll come work with you.
That is positively delightful to hear!
Nanachi, you really are special, you know.
I have some conditions.
What might they be?
Can you please not hurt them?
And help them get down to the sixth layer.
Whoops.
It seems I have done something regrettable.
That "boy-type" is a truly unprecedented specimen, you see.
I'm afraid he's already...
It wakes.
What?
Its meridians are also similar.
Very similar.
Sleep.
What are they saying?
Its vitals, too.
I-I can't move?!
I can't speak either?!
Want to see inside.
Want to see.
No good. Metal is not strong enough.
The light...
Let's use the light.
Damn it!
What is this?! What are they doing?!
Removed.
M-My arm...
Urine is also similar.
What's the composition?
Unknown.
Sufficient volume of fluid has been collected from the opening.
Sufficient.
It is even reproducing the sensation of excessive pain.
The reason is unknown.
Unknown.
Want to see the abdomen next.
Want to see.
Would also like a leg.
Reg!
Ah, damn it! Why'd it turn out like this?!
The blessed.
Blessed.
Stop it!
Don't touch me!
What are you doing?!
Stop that, all of you!
I told you, didn't I?! These kids are Papa's guests!
Reg! Nanachi!
Riko, let's hurry and get outta—
Reg?
Reg!
Riko...
How terrible!
Hey now, you guys! What's the meaning of this?!
I-I'm gonna tell Papa on you!
That is a dangerous relic.
If we hadn't induced it into lowering its guard, we couldn't have captured it.
Wait, was this on Papa's orders?
But there's no way Papa would do something so awful...
You must not come in here.
Did the Sovereign not tell you as much?
Now, this way, please...
This way, please...
Riko?
Reg! Reg!
Nanachi, Reg is...
He passed out, huh?
Riko, we're gonna take refuge outside for now.
They were planning to do this from the very start.
But Reg's arm is still inside...
Don't worry. We're absolutely getting it back.
Sure you're okay with this?
I'll tell Papa about the boat later.
Sorry about what they did to your friend.
Prushka...
You don't know what they'll do to you if you go back.
They were acting strange today,
but Papa understands me.
I'll ask him to return Reg's arm.
I'm really sorry.
And listen... I know I don't have any right to say this,
but when Reg gets all fixed up...
I mean, if everything turns out okay, then...
Oh, it's nothing.
Sorry to keep you. Please go.
Riko!
I wanna come along on your adventure!
Papa...
Papa!
Listen, Riko and her friends were—
Prushka.
You will soon be a full-fledged lady.
So please watch what is about to happen with your own eyes and ears.
This Umbra Hand is one who can be trusted,
and he will protect you while you're outside.
I can't take this anymore.
First Mitty suffered so badly, and now Reg.
We can't let that bastard keep getting his way!
He's definitely gonna come after us.
I don't know if we can swing it, but...
R-Reg...
Reg is...
Riko.
There, there. You held up well.
Riko... Nanachi...
Reg!
I smell Netherworld Stew... The burnt parts of it.
What are ya talking about?
"Smell"?
This is the fifth layer's sandstone region.
Perhaps...
Nanachi, please don't sulk like that.
I heard from Prushka.
He's a very important doll to you, isn't he?
I can't return him to his original condition,
but I'll repair him in a most adorable fashion.
Now then, let us all head back together.
That's not gonna happen. I won't let you go back.
That's the Sovereign of Annihilation's...
It's dangerous here, Nanachi. Evacuate immediately.
You know... maybe spend less time staring into holes.
You oughta look down at your feet a bit more!
In the sandstone region of the Sea of Corpses on the fifth layer,
there's a distinct odor near their nests.
Those who have not made any vomit smoke signals before coming here are likely doomed.
Seven-tailed ferocious arachnids—
the ultimate predators of the fifth layer.
Here you will find a colony of stingerheads.
Reg, Nanachi!
Riko, you all right?!
Yeah!
Are you both okay?
I'm used to the fifth layer's strains, after all.
If I focus on the force field,
I won't lose my sense of direction.
Reg, how's your wound?
It hardly hurts anymore.
What's wrong?
I feel pain in my missing fingers...
Must be what they call "phantom pain."
Anyhow, we've gotta get that arm back.
That's just one reason we can't afford to sit here.
Okay, you two, time to get ready for our next operation!
Wait, Nanachi.
They're all already...
That guy's a monster.
What? What did he just do?
"Sparagmos"... the light that returns all to the core.
It's his weapon, the one that cut off your arm and scorched off Mitty's eye.
What's the matter? Why are you hiding over there?
Let me see your faces.
Damn it!
He can read the flow of consciousnesses, too?
Probably not.
He's using some kind of trick on me!
I think he's peeking in on my sense of sight.
Papa...
Riko... What should I do?
Good gracious.
Since you were right on top of a nest, I tried to call out to you without provoking them.
But to think you were fully aware of what you were doing...
Marvelous. Marvelous.
So you already knew, huh?
Let's see if you can...
...play it cool this time!
P-Papa...
A glowstone bomb.
Coming at me prepared to explode it on top of yourself—a young man, indeed.
I'm just getting started!
I'm surprised.
You aimed at a gap in my armor, didn't you?
Hm?! Why, this is...
They're amaranthine-deceptor larvae.
There's nothing good in your head, anyway. So just let 'em devour it!
How marvelous!
He didn't know anything about our conversations.
His peeking only let him know the things I saw.
We'll show off items we've prepared, and then bombard him using totally different methods!
Right now, he doesn't have any Cartridges.
We won't get a chance like this again.
Cartridges?
Equipment to ward off the Curse of the Abyss.
Before reinforcements come, we'll settle this by hitting him hard and fast!
Such wondrous destructive power.
Good gracious, I'm envious.
I'm not done yet!
We don't know how many Sparagmoses there are.
Our only option is to make sure he can't fire it.
If he were to release enough heat underwater to burn everything up,
the water would vaporize and there'd be a huge explosion.
Ah, I see. You've surprised me.
Did you think of this yourselves?
Marvelous... Marvelous!
Now, Reg!
Just below the water is the sixth layer.
So let's try to give him a taste of it.
How dare you do that to Mitty and Nanachi!
If you like your experiments so much, then get a good taste of what one feels like!
Mar... velous...
Mar... vel...
Mar...
Mar... velous...
I'll let you live to take one last breath.
You blow that whistle...
and we'll keep going down...
Keep going...
Damn it... Why?
I'm sorry, Reg.
I forced this horrible job on you.
Papa...
Prushka?
Papa?
Papa, answer me.
Papa...
Please, Papa...
How...
How could you?
Damn it.
So what, huh?! So what?!
Papa... Papa...
It hurts!
Please... don't leave me.
Papa!
Your papa's here, Prushka.
Papa! Papa!
Thank goodness!
I won't be going anywhere.
As long as I have your love, I am immortal.
What the hell is this?!
What are you?!
Now that you mention it,
I haven't yet introduced myself, have I?
I am Bondrewd.
A cave raider of the Abyss.
People call me "The Sovereign of Dawn."
You are all truly marvelous.
You brought about the trial that we had been lacking
and have guided Prushka toward completion.
Trials make love grow stronger.
Isn't that right, Nanachi?
Wait!
Ah, heroic and adorable.
I very much want you two, as well.
Riko!
Those are Shakers that carry the strains of the third layer.
Please don't be alarmed.
Your viscera will merely churn a bit.
You bastard. What's going on?
Why are there two of you?!
Two?
The Umbra Hands are all myself.
Now, Nanachi, let us return together.
Why... Why me?
Curses are not all that one receives from the Abyss.
There is an effect we were unable to see because of the great strain it placed on the body.
As a matter of convenience...
I call this the "Blessing."
It is due to your deep emotional connection with Mitty—
her love and adoration, as it were—that your body received only the "Blessing of the Abyss."
You are the only successful instance of this.
Love. It is love, Nanachi.
You low-life scum!
Now, now. You'll wake up Prushka.
My apologies, but please allow me to take my leave.
Feel free to come anytime.
You are always welcome.
Yes, please dispose of all that is marked in crimson.
Dispose.
Papa...
Papa?
I want to see the dawn.
Yes. Let us view the dawn together.
I wanna do it together...
Together...
on an adventure...
Yes. We shall be together forevermore.
Keep it up! Almost there, Riko!
Riko, you'd be... "The Child Sovereign"!
How about something a bit cooler?
Then... "The Forehead and Glasses Sovereign!"
Huh?!
Hey, Riko, why'd you want to be a White Whistle?
Well, I wanted to become a White Whistle so I could go meet my mother.
But, you know... I wonder if that's all there is to it.
Even though I now understand the one waiting there might not be my mother, I'm all the more excited.
Who really wrote this letter?
Why does the Curse of the Abyss exist in the first place?
Who made Reg, and why?
I mean, his penis even gets bigger, you know?
What's a "penis"?
Huh?
It usually looks kind of like this...
but when Reg sees boobs or touches Nanachi, it...
Oh, you mean a "Papa Pole"!
Well, anyway...
My desire to see my mom somehow feels like it's become a reason I give people.
And I feel like now I just want a white whistle so I can descend to the sixth layer.
But, there is one thing that doesn't change.
I want to keep on having adventures with those two forever and ever!
But don't tell either of them, okay?
After all, it'll sound like I don't have any goal in mind.
You're amazing, Riko.
Riko, I think it's not so much that you wanna go see your mom,
but more that you wanna be like your mom and go on adventures with her.
What you've been feeling is way more impressive than what you've been saying!
Oh, that's it... Meeting her won't be the end.
Right! In fact, that's when it gets started!
Thanks, Prushka!
Looks like you're feeling better.
Yep. I wanna hurry and see those two and talk with them!
Hey, Riko...
That kid Reg is more amazing than even Papa's special-grade relic, right?
I bet you're gonna be the first
White Whistle armed with an Aubade.
Keep going, Riko... slowly, take your time... and don't look back.
No matter how dark the darkness of the netherworld gets, you'll be fine.
You'll brighten it up, after all.
A Flower of Dawn wilts and falls by noon, but you must push forward.
You know, Riko, I've always wanted a friend like you.
Riko, I wanna come along on your adventure!
No, Prushka.
No. No!
Don't go!
Prushka!
Riko!
You can't be moving around!
You've suffered internal injuries.
What do I do now?
Nanachi's out of it, too...
What the hell was that monster?
Once he transferred to that body, I couldn't even begin to keep up with his movements.
Not yet...
Riko?
We can't give up yet.
In the Catalog of Relics, there must be something...
Hey, what's with her?
Riko has the Catalog of Relics practically memorized.
If his relics are listed, we might find some kind of hint about how to defeat him.
Take a look. His discarded remains...
All the parts of the head are still there.
Only the mask was taken.
So he didn't swap heads?
"Zoaholic"!
What?
"Zoaholic," the soul-slave machine.
It's a relic that copies your consciousness into someone else and makes more of yourself!
But when you mix in or increase your consciousnesses, the person using it ends up going insane.
It's a special-grade relic that the Catalog started listing as lost 15 years ago.
White Whistles are supposed to only have up to grade-1 relics,
but then I remembered what Prushka said.
So that's what the mask actually was?
No...
The Zoaholic is about the size of a large room and shaped kinda like a butt.
So maybe that's not it...
You remember what the Umbra Hand from the Garden of the Flowers of Fortitude said?
The person you speak of isn't currently present.
The method for spanning layers is prone to difficulties.
So, could that mean he can transfer his consciousness even without the mask,
but he'll have problems if he spans the force field too much?
The mask is probably just a symbol...
of "The Sovereign of Dawn," Bondrewd the Novel.
It would also serve to impress on Prushka that "this is your father."
Anyway, that... "Zoaholic," was it?
That thing's super fishy...
It's the kinda thing that bastard would undoubtedly love.
That's our Nanachi! You're the brains of the team!
I-I could be wrong, you know.
Still, it's worth looking into!
Yeah!
Yeah... I suppose you're right.
If I give up before you guys do,
I won't be able to show my face to Mitty again.
All right!
If we can destroy that huge thing, it should really shake him up.
Let's do this, you two!
I'm not about to let things end like this.
We will take back our adventure!
Reg's energy source is electricity, you know!
When he woke up in Orth, it was electricity that we revived him with.
But, you know, that might've been what caused Reg to lose his memory.
If he forgets who we are...
Riko, the Incinerator will be indispensable if we're going to take him on.
The ten minutes before I pass out after I fire the first shot...
Everything depends on how many shots I can get to connect.
And don't you worry. I won't forget about you.
Reg!
Listen up.
Ido Front gets its electricity from a whirlpool.
The amount of power is nothing compared to the city's, but we can count on Reg recovering...
or so I'd like to believe.
Reg, you alone will sneak into the place that houses the power source.
Riko and I will buy you some time.
The whirlpool's located in the interior of Ido Front,
so you don't have to worry about getting sucked in, but...
Sun Sphere!
Now, come this way. This way.
How many of these bastards are there?
Now what am I supposed to do?
Hey, Nanachi...
How was the Sovereign of Dawn able to use his white whistle?
Only the original owner's supposed to be able to.
Reg did it?
Where... is here?
What happened?
Who are you?
Where?
Even peeking in on my vision won't do much when it's this dark.
Nanachi, Reg's not responding.
What was that?
It's Reg!
Since the comm device isn't working,
he's shaking things to send us a signal!
You're one hell of an optimist.
Anyway, let's hurry and find Prushka!
That thing was with Prushka.
Huh?
Meinya!
You came!
You smell like Prushka.
Meinya!
Hey!
Riko!
I think Meinya wants us to follow!
What are you talk—
That's... the right way.
What could it be?
What is this place?
It's the processing area.
"Processing"?
Of people, I mean.
The ones who are chosen are those who won't be missed:
kids from slums, or families with too many mouths to feed.
The stuff inside their heads, plus a bit of their spine...
Enough guts to live for a few days until their expiration date...
That's all they leave of them.
Everything else gets scraped off while they're still alive.
Any sensory organ that might hamper the Curse gets chopped off.
The tiny remnant of the thorough scraping process is wrapped in flesh and skin again
and stuffed into a container acting as the bones.
Drugs are used to manipulate their ecstasy and fear,
and they suffer as fleshy Curse-repellent until they die.
They're what came out of the experiments Mitty and I suffered through.
That's the truth behind what he calls Cartridges.
Nanachi...
I was truly terrified of him.
I gave in to my fear and helped him make these.
The hands of the kids who giddily kept telling me how cute I was just the day before...
Their eyes, which were filled with admiration for the Abyss...
Their jaws, grinding as they groaned in pain...
I'd carefully remove those parts and discard them.
Pretending not to see anything!
These hands have done so much!
Hurt so many!
Damn it... Why did you do this to me?!
Tell me, Bondrewd!
Marvelous.
Even under such extreme conditions,
I see your sensitivity and ability to absorb information did not diminish in the least.
You were truly worthy of receiving the Blessing.
Now, Nanachi, something far more enjoyable awaits you.
Please come back and assist me.
Why are you always like that, you insane bastard?
You're gonna cram Prushka into one of those just so you can attain that "Blessing" or whatever, aren't you?
Please! Let Prushka go!
Please put your mind at ease.
Prushka is sleeping at the moment.
I will indeed release her.
Leaving that aside,
I was fully under the impression you had come to create the raw materials for "Your Worth."
"Your Worth"?
"The life-reverberating stone"...
If I recall, that's what white whistles are carved out of.
You mentioned the Unmovable Sovereign, so I assumed she had taught you a little about that,
but I suppose she is somewhat ill-natured.
The raw material for Your Worth
is a human being.
You're kidding, right?
This base was the ruins of a former ritual site.
You see, to challenge the sixth layer and beyond,
from which one can never return,
is to surrender oneself to the netherworld.
This was a place where the preparations for that were carried out—or rather, the ritual.
Not just anyone makes for a suitable offering, however.
Without a firm resolve to sacrifice everything for the intended user,
the life-insignia won't be compatible.
The timbre of the instrument that is created also has the power to draw out the "true purpose" hidden within relics.
Doesn't sound so bad, does it?
I get it now...
You used yourself as the offering for your whistle, didn't you?
Well, well, you have keen insight.
And also the experiments that led to the Cartridges...
You came upon those ideas while fiddling with how to produce Your Worth, didn't you?
You may be more of a kindred spirit than I first imagined.
I can understand having great ambitions, but I can't even begin to forgive you.
If you're capable of making an offering of yourself,
then you should do that to make your stupid Cartridges!
This is the original me from back when I was human.
The minds of we who came after are judged as not being living things,
and thus can't be utilized as such.
Absurd, isn't it?
Still...
Even so, doing that to Prushka is just—
This was a hell of a dramatic way to buy time, but he's here now.
Huh?
Reg?! You—
My, my...
My, my, my, my.
That commotion I had been wondering about was you?
I see you've gotten all slippery while I wasn't looking.
Be careful! He's fully equipped with Cartridges!
Well, well... I see you're in fine spirits.
What the...
What the hell happened to Reg?!
He sure is fired up.
Meinya?
Nanachi, take care of things here!
Prushka! I'll be there soon!
You're a peculiar one, aren't you?
To think you'd suck even the reserve electricity dry...
Or rather than electricity, dare I say it's the concept of power that you've taken in.
I'd very much like to see the true ability of an Aubade.
Gangway!
He deflected it!
Sparagmos!
Ah. How marvelous.
I deeply regret having removed one of your arms.
I'd very much like to have that body of yours.
Reg... what's happened to you?
Forget losing your memory. You've turned into something totally different!
Whoa there.
But... but, you know...
You're an even match for Bondrewd!
While I'd love to watch you run wild a bit longer,
it would be problematic if you destroyed any more of the facility.
Far Caress!
Close.
Reg!
Damn it!
The Cartridges are spewing out consciousness,
and I can't read what he's gonna do next!
Nanachi!
What in the world have you been doin'?!
I found it!
The Zoaholic!
I still haven't found Prushka, though.
And also, right by it...
For real?!
Listen, Riko, don't show it to me under any circumstances!
If worse comes to worst...
Nanachi?
The Incinerator?
The force field's calmed down?
No!
It's all tensed up in anticipation of the destruction!
That's... the light of the core?!
He's gonna blow the whole base?!
Riko, run!
In the opposite direction from where we are!
You mustn't, Nanachi!
You stupid or something?!
Don't you forget what you treasure!
Stop!
What the...
Nanachi!
Wh-What did I...
Good grief, that was some show you put on.
Nanachi!
Riko, you okay?
I'm all right!
I see. Come back here.
She said she's fine.
What in the world happened to you?
I remember up to the point I bathed myself in electricity...
It felt like a whole bunch of "someones" were inside me.
One of them took control of my body...
Thank you, Nanachi!
You snapped me out of it!
I guess my words reached you, huh?
No, uh... your fluffiness...
Good grief...
Here! Stuff this in your ear!
A comm device?
I stuck one on your helmet, but you completely lost that thing.
Anyway, what happened to that bastard?
I'm not sure...
Maybe he got engulfed in all that?
Accompany me. This way, please.
R-Reg!
Shoot... Where am I?
Is that where I fell from?
Wh-What are these guys?!
Shakko.
Etan.
Sumiko.
Puel.
They all have names, Reg.
N-Not even a scratch?!
Well now, wasn't that what you choose?
What are you talking about?
Oh? So it wasn't deliberate, then.
Even so, I'm not happy about you destroying the ground beneath our feet.
That light of yours is a little too dangerous.
Come now.
Here, we can test out both your light and my masterpieces...
to our hearts' content.
Please, show me more—and please, yield more.
These Hollows all used to be...
Whoa there.
Now, this is most surprising.
You're even more agile now than when you were all slippery.
I'm surprised, too.
Someone made me remember how to use this body
and that I have to stop him or our adventure will end here.
It has begun.
Reg. Reg!
Nanachi!
You've already fired the Incinerator.
I'll keep this short and tell you the final plan.
I see... So it's make or break then, huh?
My, my, right after I brought you here...
How cold of you.
That bastard's overcome even the Curse with those Cartridges.
But they won't last forever.
Concentrate on evading him,
and make him use them up.
Striking him down's not the main goal.
So long as the Zoaholic isn't destroyed, he's immortal.
This Bon can move freely through the air.
The Incinerator needs a long prep time and it's unlikely to even hit him.
Make it back somehow before your time limit's up.
My, my...
Recima is finished.
She was one of my kind-hearted masterpieces.
She dreamed of becoming a princess, you know.
Isn't that adorable?
The water bastion collapsed! Watch out!
Reg! Reg!
So this is the Blessing.
Takiri. Toreithea. Nopero.
It truly was a marvelous adventure, was it not,
Prushka?
What are... you saying?
Is that...
But, Prushka...
P-Prushka...
She was crying over your dead body!
My... My, my, my.
What a strange thing for you to bring up,
considering your desire to kill me.
Come now.
Preparations for stepping into the next 2,000 years are complete.
Let us witness the dawn together.
To hell with your dawn.
As if there could be any reason to turn your daughter's love into that!
How could you?!
Let's do this, Nanachi!
Got it! On with the plan!
Riko. Can you hear me?
Riko! Please respond!
Riko?!
P-Prushka...
Prushka...
It hurts...
It hurts!
How are things going, Gueira?
I'm not sure about this one, boss.
The Curse affected her too deeply and even her sense of self got stripped away.
Look, do ya know who ya are?
Whoa!
I know she's the daughter of an Umbra Hand,
but she was in the carrier crash.
Way things stand, makin' use of her would just be cruel.
Wouldn't it be better to just kill 'er off?
A prayer cannot be born from one who knows only of joy.
O child of suffering who curses life itself,
there is something only you can accomplish.
Your name shall be "Prushka."
The meaning of the word is "flower of dawn."
I'm Papa. I am your Papa.
Prushka.
Come on, Prushka!
Time for your medicine.
Come 'ere.
How's she doing, Gueira?
She's been like this the whole time.
Prushka, I've brought you a friend today.
Meinastilim... It's called a "Child of Change."
Mei...
Meinya...
My, my, have you taken a liking to it?
You mustn't put it in your mouth, now.
Oh, she came out.
Meinya...
Prushka, I see you've found something that you like.
From this moment forward, your world will begin to change.
From now on, you will be forged by each and every step you take.
Today is the day of your birth.
This is the start of your adventure.
Is that tasty?
I can eat it.
I see. Whatta waste...
I mean, there's so much tasty stuff in the Abyss.
"Tasty"... can be eaten?
That's right.
I wonder what "tasty" is...
Think it tastes like you, Meinya?
Pee-ew!
Meinya!
Wait, Meinya!
You can't go in there!
All right!
The nails on both hands, her upper left arm,
and all her baby teeth were broken.
Her spinal cord didn't end up gettin' crushed, at least.
But as to whether her psyche can be brought back...
It will be fine.
Prushka's psyche sprang forth from a far deeper place.
I am sure it will return soon.
Let us watch over her with care.
My hair's all twirly now, huh?
Why were you totally fine, Meinya?
I've gotta investigate!
Pretty amazing, huh?!
When I take a sniff of Meinya's scent,
I can see fuzzy stuff in places
I can't usually make out anything!
You never learn, do you?
So, is the boss okay with just letting you run wild?
It's fine! Keep this a secret from Papa, okay?!
Good grief...
Meinya! Use those eyes that see everything and watch!
Watch my adventures!
Some special, important visitors are on their way.
They're people who are going to help me.
Prushka, I would like you to keep them company.
Oh, that's right.
One of them is the daughter of a White Whistle just like you.
You need not fret.
I'm sure you'll become friends in no time at all.
Oh, come on, Papa!
I mean, you already have me!
Hey, Meinya, those people came here all the way from that place called the surface, right?
I wonder what seeing an actual dawn would be like...
Well, I'm surely better at cleaning than them!
The trees grow upside down, and the waterfalls even flow upward!
Really?!
Even in the fifth layer I've never seen anything like that!
You know, I was at this place called Belchero Orphanage, and...
I listened...
I learned...
of scenery I'd never heard of.
Creatures I'd never heard of.
Precious friends.
Fun.
Fun!
Faces I'd never made!
Words I'd never used!
I want more...
More...
More... together.
My arms...
My legs...
My... What is that anyway...?
It hurts.
The pain keeps getting worse...
Papa's pain...
his feelings...
are flooding into me.
My pain is turning into Papa's strength.
Papa...
Papa, I'm here with you.
Now, no matter how hard things get,
no matter how dark the night is,
we can overcome it together.
It seems these claws can pierce through your thin spots.
Although your body is excessively durable,
it's most helpful that even your weak points are fashioned after a human's.
You said that... even my pain... is an imitation.
Indeed. You are truly well made.
Down to the warmth of your insides.
If this pain is just an imitation,
I can still move!
I'll show you... that this will of mine is far from fake!
So, Papa...
Just one thing... Can I ask just one thing of you?
Reg, Riko! Now!
I... You know, I...
I want you to make peace with Riko and her friends.
It's not good to fight.
After all, we're gonna go on an adventure together.
Together!
Reg! Reg!
Damn it!
Don't die on me!
Nanachi...
Don't try to speak!
I'll fix you no matter what it takes.
N-Nanachi, your hand...
I've... calmed down a bit.
Sorry... I've reached my limit.
Take care... of Riko.
You have surprised me.
To think it was possible to operate the severed arm.
You all exhausted your strength, used your wits,
and took action most brilliantly.
It was truly moving.
Enough of your blabbering.
From the looks of it, no one's coming out to protect that body,
which must mean you no longer have Umbra Hands who can fight.
So now we're free to destroy the remaining facilities, including the Zoaholic.
There are so many of you now, we wouldn't be able to kill you even if we tried.
But your grand aspirations end here.
Serves you right!
Why, not at all.
Your prayers...
Your ardent desire to choose your own paths and push forward...
They surpassed my own.
Although it is most regrettable that this body has been destroyed,
crossing paths and having the chance to clash with you was an unparalleled joy.
That you will all continue on beyond here is my new aspiration.
It's useless saying anything to you, huh? Damn you.
How unbelievably pathetic...
I've long dreamed of the day we'd kill each other in battle, and yet...
Ah, I am glad things did not turn out that way—truly.
Nanachi, come now, raise your head.
May...
May your journey overflow with Curses and Blessings.
Shut up already.
My... You truly are adorable.
It's ironic...
If I didn't fall for your honeyed words, then I...
Looks like you woke up. That's a relief.
Nanachi...
I took a peek, and your insides weren't injured.
Judging from how you're looking, you'll be fine.
Did we do it?
Yeah.
There are still some Umbra Hands left, but they no longer have the power to get in our way.
More importantly...
I can't take it!
Riko...
Reg!
Your tummy!
As you can see, I'm all right.
More importantly...
Prushka, you know...
She's so warm, but...
Look! Even though she has a pulse...
Huh? Her pulse is...
Does facing upward hurt?!
No!
Prushka's spilling out!
Why? All this...
Hm? What's that?
Prushka... is that you?
Seriously? Is that...
That's the sense I get.
I wonder why...
It's strange.
What? Hey, what's wrong?
M-my belly's hot... What is this?!
A "life-reverberating stone." For real?
But something like this would never happen unless the person who got packed wanted it.
How could someone care about another person even while having the Curse forced on them?
And it was such a short period of time, too.
Prushka...
Riko.
Can I see that?
Look. Leaving it exposed is, uh... probably not good.
N-Nanachi...
You're probably feeling conflicted,
but I'm certain that Prushka wants this to be entrusted to you.
You're the only one who can use it.
So though it doesn't look too pretty...
That's your white whistle.
Nanachi!
About ten shots left, huh?
That reminds me, I haven't eaten anything...
Pretty sure you ate your fill.
The power at the base is still out, you know.
Are both of you ready?
Crying, eating... You're a busy one, aren't you?
Hey, Nanachi...
That bastard...
I should've shattered that mask.
Are we okay?
We've come to an understanding of sorts.
Besides, I'm gonna respect our team leader's decision.
Come on, hurry!
Our adventure is about to begin!
To those who offer up their bodies and challenge the chasm for which even darkness is no match,
the Abyss is said to provide all.
Life and death, Curses and Blessings—all of it.
Prushka, let's go together.
At the end of their journey,
what fate will they choose to meet?
That can only be decided by the challengers themselves.
It's finally time for our last dive.
Yeah, at long last.
It's the beginning of the final journey
from which we can never return.
Let's do this!
Yeah!
No matter how dark the darkness of the netherworld gets, you'll be fine.
You'll brighten it up, after all.
Riko, push forward!