CLEANING
Marulk, go and clean those three's rooms.
But everyone's out on an expedition right now...
It's fine. Just go in and tidy up.
Those guys won't do in on their own.
I'm counting on you.
Understood, Master!
I'll start with Yelme's room.
Excuse me...
Yelme-san, I'm amazed you can sleep in this mess.
Oh, Yelme-san!
All right, next is Zapo-san.
I need to air out his futon... huh?
His bed is...
...up there, huh?
All right! Just Simred's left and I'll be done!
The laundry's sure piling up in here.
He could have just brought these out yesterday.
There's even more under the bed.
That was truly awful...
Truly...
That place couldn't be called a room.
It was some sort of nether realm.