MEMORY
With that, the laundry is done.
I wonder what would have happened to me if I hadn't come here.
If I hadn't met her...
What would have...
This was an airship.
These people were the crew.
This person was my father.
Soon, I too will...
It's just as I said. They were completely wiped out.
Well, the types who actually listen to advice...
...wouldn't have come here in the first place.
Who is that?
It seems the fuel hasn't spilt out.
In that case, it shouldn't be a problem to just leave it.
A whistle?
Oh?
There are survivors?
Just you?
You look awfully comfortable in there.
If you simply remain there...
...you'll eventually be able to see your comrades again.
At the very least, you'll return to the soil of the netherworld.
Oh, I had heard you guys could understand the common language.
If you wish to continue living, come out here.
Well? What will you do?
I see. Goodbye.
This is pathetic.
Welcome to the Abyss.
Master! My apologies!
You were sleeping soundly, huh?
Were you having a scary dream?
Yes.
It was scary.
It was scary, but...
It was a heartwarming dream.