ERRAND
We have bussiness to attend to.
In the meantime, go buy what's on this list.
You'll be punished if you make any mistakes.
Master, this map is completely unintelligible.
Well, I more or less know the place.
I'll take you there.
Thank you very much! Umm...
Nat. And you?
I'm Marulk.
Marulk?
That's kind of a boyish name.
Huh?
Well anyway, this pole-looking thing...
...is probably supposed to be that chimney.
In that case, there's a shortcut if we go this way.
You seem to know the area well, Nat-san.
Orth is like my backyard.
I'm glad I met you, Nat-san!
S-Sure...
Can you jump it?
Yes.
Don't overdo it.
No, don't worry about me.
Careful!
What a nice scent.
Nat-san?
Sorry!
Ah, it's this shop here.
Oh, it's just Habo-san's place.
Thank you very much.
Let me show my gratitude in some way.
If it's within my ability, anything is fine.
Anything?
Dumbass! Hurry and finish your errand and go home!
Nat-san?
See you later!
Excuse me.